A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Executive Office-Governor, Records, 2005-2009
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Executive Office-Governor, Records 2005-2009
The Library of Virginia
44695
15.75 cu. ft. (45 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, accession 44695 transferred on 14 January 2010.
Biographical Information
The Executive Office is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state government. Members of the Executive Office include the Governor, Chief of Staff, Counselor to the Governor and their assistants. The Governor is the Chief Executive of the Commonwealth and chief advocate for annual legislative and budget priorities. The Executive Office-Governor records during Governor Timothy M. Kaine's administration (2006-2010) were maintained by Sherrie Harrington, Confidential Assistant to the Governor.
Scope and Content
The Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Executive Office-Governor, Records are housed in 45 boxes. The collection is arranged into three (3) series. Series have been designated for: I. Weekly Status Reports; II. State Budget Files; and III. Briefing Binders and Reports. These records include agreements, briefing books, reports, correspondence, memorandums, budget documents, agendas, handouts, invitations, talking points, and speeches. This collection contains the weekly reports, briefing books and budgetary records of Governor Kaine (2006-2010).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Cabinet Weekly Reports, 2006-2009
II. State Budget Files, 2005-2009
III. Briefing Books and Reports, 2006-2009
Related Material
Office of the Governor-Tim Kaine
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration Electronic Files, Email, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009). This collection documents the email of the Kaine Administration (2006-2010). It includes agreements, briefing books, reports, correspondence, memorandums, agendas, electronic mail, handouts, invitations, meeting notes, press releases (drafts), spreadsheets (budget), talking points, and speeches. The Library of Virginia Email Project - Governor Tim Kaine Portal provides access to the Kaine email collection and includes guides to other Kaine administration records.
The Governor Tim Kaine Administration Web Archive Collection, 2006-2010 contains archived versions of websites for the Governor's Office, his initiative sites, and the sites of his cabinet secretaries. Also included are the related sites for the First Lady (Anne Holton), as well as the Lt. Governor (Bill Bolling), and Attorney General (Bob McDonnell and William C. Mims), two statewide officials elected in the same cycle as Governor Kaine.
The Timothy M. Kaine Administration (2006-2010) Cabinet Weekly Reports contains the weekly reports submitted to the Governor and Chief of Staff by the Governor's Cabinet, including the Secretaries of Administration (Viola Baskerville), Agriculture and Forestry (Robert S. Bloxom), Commerce and Trade (Patrick O. Gottschalk), Commonwealth (Daniel C. LeBlanc, Jan-Mar. 2006 and Katherine K. Hanley (Mar. 2006-2010), Education (Dr. Thomas R. Morris), Finance (Jody Wagner, 2006-2008 and Richard D. Brown, 2008-2010), Health and Human Resources (Marilyn Tavenner), Natural Resources (Preston Bryant), Public Safety (John W. Marshall), Technology (Aneesh Chopra, 2006-2009 and Leonard M. Pomata, 2009-2010), and Transportation (Pierce Homer). Also included are reports by the Assistant to the Governor for Commonwealth Preparedness (Robert Crouch), Office of Constituent Services (Marc Cheatham, 2006-2007 and Amber Amato, 2007-2010), Press Office, Policy Office and Virginia Liaison Office. Reports were submitted each Thursday and placed in a binder for the Governor that he took with him at the end of the day on Friday. A second copy of the report was made for the Chief of Staff. The level of detail varied for each cabinet officer and items of importance were highlighted by staff for the Governor. Each report contains information on legislation, Governor's initiatives/special projects, agency matters/operations, events/agency visits, audits/investigations/compliance, stakeholder issues and pending decisions. Governor Kaine wrote handwritten notes and/or marked-up some reports with post-it notes and requested follow up information from the person submitting the report. Those questions and answers are included in this series. This series provides a weekly account of the issues and policy decisions of the Kaine Administration.
Live Websites
The Virginia General Assembly's Legislative Information System contains a searchable databases for bills and resolutions from 1994 to the present and reports to the general assembly. It also includes links to the Code of Virginia, Virginia Administrative Code, Constitution of Virginia, Charters, Authorities, Compacts and Uncodified Acts.
The Virginia State Budget Portal provides information about Budget Bills, Budget Amendments, and Committee Reports related to the budget from 1996 to the present.
The Virginia Department of Planning and Budget assists the Governor's Office, General Assembly, and state agencies develop and implement the budget. The website contains information on Virginia's budget from 2000 to the present.
The Secretary of Finance's website contains monthly revenue reports (FY 2000 to the present) and presentations to the joint money committees (1999 to the present).
Contents List
- I. Cabinet Weekly Reports, 2006-2009., Extent: 7.0 cubic feet (20 boxes). (Box 1-20)
  The Cabinet Weekly Reports series is housed in 20 boxes, arranged chronologically and contains the weekly reports submitted to the Governor and Chief of Staff by the Governor's Cabinet, including the Secretaries of Administration (Viola Baskerville), Agriculture and Forestry (Robert S. Bloxom), Commerce and Trade (Patrick O. Gottschalk), Commonwealth (Daniel C. LeBlanc, Jan-Mar. 2006 and Katherine K. Hanley (Mar. 2006-2010), Education (Dr. Thomas R. Morris), Finance (Jody Wagner, 2006-2008 and Richard D. Brown, 2008-2010), Health and Human Resources (Marilyn Tavenner), Natural Resources (Preston Bryant), Public Safety (John W. Marshall), Technology (Aneesh Chopra, 2006-2009 and Leonard M. Pomata, 2009-2010), and Transportation (Pierce Homer). Also included are reports by the Assistant to the Governor for Commonwealth Preparedness (Robert Crouch), Office of Constituent Services (Marc Cheatham, 2006-2007 and Amber Amato, 2007-2010), Press Office, Policy Office and Virginia Liaison Office. Reports were submitted each Thursday and placed in a binder for the Governor that he took with him at the end of the day on Friday. A second copy of the report was made for the Chief of Staff. The level of detail varied for each cabinet officer and items of importance were highlighted by staff for the Governor. Each report contains information on legislation, Governor's initiatives/special projects, agency matters/operations, events/agency visits, audits/investigations/compliance, stakeholder issues and pending decisions. Governor Kaine wrote handwritten notes and/or marked-up some reports with post-it notes and requested follow up information from the person submitting the report. Those questions and answers are included in this series. This series provides a weekly account of the issues and policy decisions of the Kaine Administration.
  The Timothy M. Kaine Administration (2006-2010) Cabinet Weekly Reports have been digitized and are availble online.
  Notable topics and issues include: avian flu, Blue Crab disaster relief, Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission (BRAC), Capitol Square and Capital Building renovations, Civil Rights Memorial, Dulles Corridor Rail Project, 8th and 9th Street Office Buildings, Early Childhood Education, Education for a Lifetime, eVa, Governor's Campus Security Conference, Health IT, Hurricane Evaluation and Sheltering Task Force, Presidential Inaugural Planning, Land Conservation, minority procurement and SWAM (Small, Women and Minority) business, Outlying Landing Field, Public Safety Memorial Commission, Telework, gubernatorial transition, tribal recognition for Virginia Indians, Virginia Information Technologies Agency (VITA) problems, Virginia Tech shooting, and Weekly Ford Plant Reports (closure of Norfolk Assembly Plant).
  - 26 January 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 2 February 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 9 February 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 16 February 2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 23 February 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2 March 2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 9 March 2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 16 March 2006 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 23 March 2006 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 30 March 2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 6 April 2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 13 April 2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 20 April 2006 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 27 April 2006 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 4 May 2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 11 May 2006 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 18 May 2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 25 May 2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1 June 2006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 15 June 2006 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 22 June 2006 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 6 July 2006 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 13 July 2006 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 20 July 2006 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 27 July 2006 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 3 August 2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 10 August 2006 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 17 August 2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 24 August 2006 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 31 August 2006 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 7 September 2006 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 14 September 2006 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 21 September 2006 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 28 September 2006 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 5 October 2006 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 12 October 2006 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 19 October 2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 26 October 2006 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 2 November 2006 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 9 November 2006 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 16 November 2006 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 30 November 2006 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 7 December 2006 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 4 January 2007 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 11 January 2007 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 18 January 2007 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 25 January 2007 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 2 February 2007 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 9 February 2007 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 16 February 2007 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 23 February 2007 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 2 March 2007 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 9 March 2007 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 16 March 2007 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 22 March 2007 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 29 March 2007 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 6 April 2007 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 13 April 2007 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 20 April 2007 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 26 April 2007 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 10 May 2007 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 17 May 2007 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 25 May 2007 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1 June 2007 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 8 June 2007 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 15 June 2007 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 22 June 2007 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 29 June 2007 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 13 July 2007 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 20 July 2007 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 27 July 2007 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 3 August 2007 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 10 August 2007 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 17 August 2007 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 24 August 2007 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 31 August 2007 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 7 September 2007 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 14 September 2007 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 21 September 2007 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 28 September 2007 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 5 October 2007 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 12 October 2007 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 19 October 2007 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 26 October 2007 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 2 November 2007 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 9 November 2007 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 16 November 2007 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 30 November 2007 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 7 December 2007 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 14 December 2007 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 21 December 2007 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 11 January 2008 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 18 January 2008 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 25 January 2008 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1 February 2008 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 8 February 2008 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 15 February 2008 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 22 February 2008 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 29 February 2008 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - 7 March 2008 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - 14 March 2008 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - 21 March 2008 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 28 March 2008 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 4 April 2008 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 11 April 2008 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 18 April 2008 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 25 April 2008 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 2 May 2008 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 9 May 2008 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 16 May 2008 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 22 May 2008 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 30 May 2008 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 6 June 2008 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 13 June 2008 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 20 June 2008 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 27 June 2008 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 3 July 2008 (Governor's copy) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 3 July 2008 (Chief of Staff's copy) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 11 July 2008 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - 18 July 2008 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 25 July 2008 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1 August 2008 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 8 August 2008 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 15 August 2008 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 22 August 2008 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 29 August 2008 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 5 September 2008 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 12 September 2008 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 19 September 2008 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 26 September 2008 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 3 October 2008 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - 10 October 2008 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - 17 October 2008 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - 24 October 2008 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - 31 October 2008 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - 7 November 2008 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 14 November 2008 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 21 November 2008 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - 5 December 2008 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 12 December 2008 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 19 December 2008 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - 9 January 2009 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - 16 January 2009 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - 23 January 2009 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - 30 January 2009 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - 6 February 2009 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - 13 February 2009 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - 20 February 2009 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 27 February 2009 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 6 March 2009 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 13 March 2009 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - 20 March 2009 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 27 March 2009 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - 3 April 2009 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - 10 April 2009 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - 17 April 2009 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - 24 April 2009 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - 1 May 2009 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - 8 May 2009 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 15 May 2009 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - 22 May 2009 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - 29 May 2009 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 5 June 2009 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - 12 June 2009 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - 19 June 2009 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - 26 June 2009 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - 2 July 2009 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - 10 July 2009 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - 17 July 2009 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - 24 July 2009 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - 31 July 2009 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - 7 August 2009 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - 14 August 2009 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - 21 August 2009 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - 28 August 2009 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - 4 September 2009 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - 11 September 2009 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - 18 September 2009 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - 25 September 2009 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - 2 October 2009 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - 9 October 2009 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - 16 October 2009 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - 23 October 2009 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - 30 October 2009 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - 6 November 2009 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - 20 November 2009 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - 4 December 2009 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - 11 December 2009 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - 18 December 2009 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- II. State Budget Files, 2005-2009., Extent: 5.95 cubic feet (17 boxes). (Box 21-37)
  The State Budget Files series is housed in 17 boxes and is arranged chronologically by budget cycle. This series documents the budgetary process during the Kaine Administration. Subjects include: Kaine's 2006 transportation plan, 2006 budget stalemate, 2007 electricity regulation, 2007 transportation compromise, development of the 2008-2010 biennium budget, 2008 special session on transportation, 2009 budget amendments and the development of the 2010-2012 biennium budget.
  Notable documents on the 2006 budget stalemate include: email from Brian Shepard describing a potential continuity of operations timeline for June 2006; memorandum to Governor Kaine from Larry Roberts, 23 May 2006, describing the Governor's authority in the event that Virginia does not have a budget in place as of July 1, 2006; and notes from 6 May 2006 meeting; draft of an advisory opinion written by Attorney General Robert F. McDonnell, dated 23 May 2006, on the Governor's authority to initiate a spending plan in the event a budget bill is not passed by July 1, 2006 (all b22, f3).
  Notable documents on the 2007 electricity regulation include: memorandum to Governor Kaine from Hullihen Williams Moore, former chair of the Virginia State Corporation Commission, 8 March 2007 on SB 1416; memorandum to Governor Kaine through Mark Rubin from Steve Walz, 14 March 2007 on proposed amendments to HB 3068 and SB 1416; Recommended Changes to Electric Re-regulation Legislation HB 3068/SB 1416, 20 March 2007; and Enrolled SB 1416/HB 3068 Electric Re-regulation Analysis (all b24, f2)
  Notable documents on the 2007 transportation compromise include: email to Governor Kaine from Deputy Chief of Staff Wayne Turnage, 9 March 2007, on Kaine's 11 March 2007 meeting with his transportation team. Email describes the team's 3 camps on the issue: hardliners who believe that the Republicans will not compromise and the Governor may have to veto the bill; advisors who believe the administration is in a strong position to cut a deal with House Republicans; and the third group is unsure if the administration can cut a deal and the governor may have to sign a flawed bill. Email also includes as an attachment a Status Report on Transportation Strategic Plan (b24, f4); memorandum to Governor Kaine from Mark Rubin, undated, outline of structure of negotiations on transportation bill (b24, f5); and Gov. Kaine's handwritten notes on the transportation bill, undated, but probably used for meetings with groups in Northern Virginia and Hampton Roads (b24, f5)
  Notable documents on the development of the 2008-2010 biennium budget include: Governor's Biennial Budget Memos, Summer 2007, Briefing Book (b25, f1-f2) - arranged by Secretary, lists objectives, a review of performances, Secretariat priorities and opportunities, and how priorities are to be funded; Pre-K Communications Plan, July 2007 (b25, f3); Email to Brian Shepard, Director of Policy, from Governor Kaine, 23 April 2007 - subject: Policy Development Agenda through Year End (b25, f3); and Budget Meeting Agendas and Supporting Documents for meetings with Governor Kaine, October-December 2007 (b26-b27).
  Notable documents on the 2008 special session on transportation include: Briefing Book - 2008 Transportation Special Session (volume)(b30); Email from Gov. Kaine to senior staff giving his thoughts on tax information and transportation plan, 20 March 2008 (b30, f1); and Transportation Poll - Report to Governor Tim Kaine, by Pete Brodnitz, Benenson Strategy Group, 5 April 2008 (b30, f1).
  Notable documents on the development of the 2010-2012 biennium budget include: Talking Points on Budget Outlook, 6 May 2009, 15 June 2009 (b34, f2); and Budget Meeting Agendas and Supporting Documents for meetings with Governor Kaine, June-December 2009 (b34-b37).
  - Budget Files-General, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Budget Files-General, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Budget Files-General, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - 2006 Special Session I: House Bill 5004, 27 March 2006 (Volume) (Box 21)
  - Transportation, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Transportation, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Budget Files, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Continuity of Operations Planning (no budget), 2006 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Budget Files, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Joint Conference Committee Report on House Bill 5002, 2006 Special Session I, 19 June 2006 (part one) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Joint Conference Committee Report on House Bill 5002, 2006 Special Session I, 19 June 2006 (part two) (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Executive Amendments to the 2006-2008 Biennial Budget (volume) (Box 22)
  - Special Session I, 2006 Virginia Acts of Assembly [budget bill], 30 June 2006 (volume) (Box 23)
  - Strategic Asset Management, Commonwealth of Virginia, by Goldman Sachs, 15 September 2006 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 2006 Budget Amendments (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - House Document No. 1, The Budget Bill, 2007 Session (volume) (Box 23)
  - 2007 Legislative Files (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - HB 3068 and SB 1416, Electricity Regulation, 2007 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Transportation Compromise (HB 3202), 2007 (part one) (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Transportation Compromise (HB 3202), 2007 (part two) (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Transportation Compromise (HB 3202), 2007 (part three) (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Budget Reductions for FY2008, 2007 (part one) (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Budget Reductions for FY2008, 2007 (part two) (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Meeting, Discussion of Secretarial Budget Reduction Plans for FY2008, 19 September 2007 (part one) (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Meeting, Discussion of Secretarial Budget Reduction Plans for FY2008, 19 September 2007 (part two) (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - 2008 Pre-Session Budget Materials
    - Governor's Biennial Budget Memos, Briefing Book, Summer 2007 (part one) (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Biennial Budget Memos, Briefing Book, Summer 2007 (part two) (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Education, 2007 (part one) (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Education, 2007 (part two) (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Education, 2007 (part three) (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - K-12 Target Funding Discussion, 10 October 2007 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Health, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Mental Health and Virginia Tech related legislation, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Natural Resources, 2007 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Transportation, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Workforce Development, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 4 October 2007 (part one) (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 4 October 2007 (part two) (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 16 October 2007 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 1-2 November 2007 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Strategic Planning Meeting - Senior Staff, 7 November 2007 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 7-8 November 2007 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 12 November 2007 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 13 November 2007 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Preschool Initiative (VPI): Current Implementation and Potential Changes, 13 November 2007 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 16 November 2007 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 20 November 2007 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 21 November 2007 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 26 November 2007 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 27 November 2007 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 29 November 2007 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 30 November 2007 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 1 December 2007 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Budget Meeting with Governor, 3 December 2007 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Governor Kaine's Proposed Budget for 2008 and the 2008-2010 Biennium, 17 December 2007 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Records, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - 2008 Session
    - Governor's 2008 Legislative Agenda and Bills (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - 2008 Session, House Bill No. 29 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Cabinet Meeting - Revenue and Budget Picture, 1 February 2008 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Budget Balancing Plan, 7 February 2008 (Box 29, Folder 1)